Guide to the John Graves Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- Personal Materials, circa 1920-2002; 1938-1999
  - Artifacts, 1957-1973, undated
    - Rubber mold for belt buckle (2 pieces) (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Ceramic mold for belt buckle (1 piece) (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - "Silent Partner" inflatable figures (2) (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Tan cotton baseball cap worn by Graves (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Plastic slide box labeled "John Graves' Hardscrabble – 1973, photos by Bill Wittliff," separation sheet (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Royal Standard typewriter used by Graves (Box 41)
    - Three ring binders (8) separated from contents (Box 42)
    - Three ring binders (4) separated from contents (Box 43)
    - Fly reels (5) handmade by Graves (Box 48)
    - Canoe paddle Graves used on 1957 Brazos River trip (Item 1)
    - Small green camp tent Graves used on 1957 Brazos River trip (Box 49)
- Clippings, circa 1940-2004, undated
  Photocopies—and the originals, when available—of newspaper and magazine clippings related mostly to Graves' writing career can be found in this series. The clippings are filed in chronological order. A number of issues of entire magazines are kept in Box 47, due to their size.
  - circa 1940-1959 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - circa 1960-1961 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - circa 1962-1972 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - 1974 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - 1975-1979 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - 1980 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - 1981 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - 1982 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - circa 1983-1992 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - 1996-1997 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - 2001-2004 (Box 44, Folder 11)
- Writings by Others, 1942-2002, undated
  This series consists mainly of draft photocopies and printouts of other people's novels, essays, screenplays and poetry. Also included are correspondence, clippings, research, notes and page proofs. A handful are essays written about Graves, but the majority of the files are creative works that Graves has proofread or for which he has offered promotional comments.
  The typescript "A Texas Rancher in Durango, Mexico" may not be viewed without permission from John Graves or Bill Wittliff.
  - All for Love by Turk Pipkin - printout, 2002 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - "Construction" by Donald Bartholomew – corrected printout, notes, undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - "The Ecotopian Landscape of John Graves" by Don Scheese - photocopy of essay, undated (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Grover, Dorys Crow – photocopies of two published stories and one conference paper, 1975-1985 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - "John Graves" by unknown author - photocopy of essay, undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - "John Graves Tribute, November 11, 2000" by William Broyles - printout of speech (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Las Capeas by Euginio Noel - annotated book, corrected typescript of translation, 1952 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - "The Last of the Old Time Cowboys" by unknown author - photocopy of essay, undated (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Legends of the Fall screenplay by Bill Wittliff - first draft, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - McNeal, Tom - poetry, correspondence, 1942 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Myself and Others by Alexander Brook - correspondence, clippings, will, 1977-1978 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Myself and Others by Alexander Brook - corrected typescript, 1977-1978 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - "Paisano" by Bill Porterfield - research, notes, miscellaneous typescript pages, undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - 'Swede Johnson Papers' - clipping, miscellaneous manuscript pages, 1942, undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Texas Bound anthology – correspondence, photocopies of contents, 1997 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - A Texas Rancher in Durango, Mexico by Thomas P. Harrison III, - bound typescript with corrections by Graves - RESTRICTED, undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Tom Northway by Marshall Terry – correspondence, page proofs, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - "Undaunted Courage" teleplay by Bill Wittliff - photocopy of script, 1997 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Untitled essay about Graves by unknown author – photocopied typescript fragment, undated (Box 46, Folder 7)